viralchronicle.com 2016-10-11

# Privacy Policy | ViralChronicle

## Data Controller and Owner

Viral Chronicle LLC, contact@viralchronicle.com 

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage data, Geographic position and Email address. Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection. The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application. Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User. Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services. Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner. 

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data. The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. 

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller. 

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data. 

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Advertising, Analytics, Commercial affiliation, Content commenting, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Traffic optimization and distribution, Infrastructure monitoring, Heat mapping, Hosting and backend as a service, Location-based interactions, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Displaying content from external platforms, Managing contacts and sending messages, Handling payments and Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting. The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document. 

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services: 

  * ### Advertising

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests. This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below. Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services. 

#### Taboola Monetize Content (Taboola Inc.)

Taboola is an advertising service provided by Taboola Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy)

#### Google AdSense (Google)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of this Application and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered. Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en). Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://google.com/privacy/ads/)

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior. 

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Quantcast Measure (Quantcast Corporation)

Quantcast Measure is an analytics service provided by Quantcast Corporation. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy)

#### Piwik (This Application)

Piwik is an analytics software used by this Application to analyze data directly without the help of third parties. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. [Privacy Policy](http://piwik.org/)

  * ### Commercial affiliation

These services allow this Application to display advertisements for third party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics. Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with this Application. For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service. 

#### Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)

Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_rel_topic?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496)

  * ### Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Application. Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments. If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when users do not use the content commenting service. 

#### Facebook Comments (Facebook)

Facebook Comments is a content commenting service provided by Facebook Inc. enabling the User to leave comments and share them on the Facebook platform. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

  * ### Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)

The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of this Application. 

#### Google Website Optimizer (Google)

Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc. Google may use Personal Data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Optimizely (Optimizely, Inc.)

Optimizely is an A/B testing service provided by Optimizely, Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.optimizely.com/privacy)

  * ### Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them. If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it. 

#### Instagram widget (Instagram, Inc.)

Instagram is an image visualization service provided by Instagram, Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)

  * ### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction. Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment. 

#### Outbrain (Outbrain Inc.)

Outbrain is a payment service provided by Outbrain Inc. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy-713/)

  * ### Heat mapping

Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior. 

#### Crazyegg (Crazyegg)

Crazyegg is a heat mapping service provided by Crazy Egg Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy)

  * ### Hosting and backend as a service

These services have the purpose of hosting data and files that enable this Application to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Application. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored. 

#### DigitalOcean (DigitalOcean Inc.)

DigitalOcean is a hosting service provided by DigitalOcean Inc. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.digitalocean.com/legal/privacy/)

#### Heroku (Heroku, Inc.)

Heroku is a hosting service provided by Heroku, Inc. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.heroku.com/policy/privacy)

  * ### Infrastructure monitoring

These services allow this Application to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved. Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of this Application. 

#### Bugsnag (Bugsnag Inc.)

Bugsnag is a monitoring service provided by Bugsnag Inc. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://bugsnag.com/docs/privacy)

#### New Relic (New Relic)

New Relic is a monitoring service provided by New Relic Inc. The way New Relic is integrated means that it filters all traffic of this Application, i.e., communication between the Application and the User's browser or device, while also allowing analytical data on this Application to be collected. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://newrelic.com/privacy)

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application. The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network. If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it. 

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

#### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://about.pinterest.com/privacy/)

#### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Location-based interactions

#### Geolocation (This Application)

This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services. Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by this Application. Personal Data collected: Geographic position. 

  * ### Managing contacts and sending messages

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User. These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message. 

#### Mailchimp (Mailchimp)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailchimp Inc. Personal Data collected: Email address. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

#### Sendgrid (Sendgrid)

Sendgrid is an email address management and message sending service provided by Sendgrid Inc. Personal Data collected: Email address. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://sendgrid.com/email_policy.html)

  * ### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting

These services allow this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User. This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity. 

#### Twitter Remarketing (Twitter)

Twitter Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Twitter advertising network. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405)

  * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

These services allow this Application to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance. Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Application and the User's browser. Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred. 

#### CloudFlare (Cloudflare)

CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc. The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Application, i.e., communication between this Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Application to be collected. Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy)

## Information about Cookies

  * ### Advertising

These Cookies are necessary for the functioning of the services filed under the section ”Advertising”. 

#### exchange_uid, _drt_, FLC, id, __gads

Google AdSense Cookies. 

  * ### Analytics

These Cookies are necessary for the functioning of the services filed under the section ”Analytics”. 

#### _ut*, _ga

Google Analytics Cookies. 

#### _pk_*

Piwik Cookies. 

  * ### Infrastructure monitoring

These Cookies are necessary for the functioning of the services filed under the section ”Infrastructure monitoring”. 

#### JSESSIONID

New Relic Cookies. 

Since the installation of third party Cookies and other tracking systems through the services used within this Application can not be technically controlled by the Owner, any specific references to Cookies and tracking systems installed by third parties are to be considered indicative. In order to obtain complete information, consult the privacy policy for the respective third party services listed in this document. 

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services. The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests. To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.
